Finding Aid for Michigan Municipal League records, 1928-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Municipal League records 1928-1977
Michigan Municipal League.
2 linear feet
85324 Bm 2
Advisory organization to Michigan local governments; correspondence, reports, and clippings and scrapbooks relating to organizational activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the organization (donor no. 874 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Founded in 1899, the Michigan Municipal League is the Michigan association of cities and villages. The League is a nonpartisan organization working through cooperative effort to strengthen the quality of municipal government and administration by providing technical assistance and information to local officials regarding municipal issues; improving the training and education of these officials; preserving the home rule philosophy of municipal government, and creating a greater public understanding of municipal responsibilities, governance and administration. (from the website of the Michigan Municipal League)
The records of the Michigan Municipal League include correspondence with city officials in the period of 1928-1929. These include Laird J. Troyer, mayor of Lansing, Alvah P. Cady, Benton Harbor city attorney, Earnest C. Brooks, mayor of Holland, and Ganson Taggart, Grand Rapids city attorney. There are also staff field reports, 1934-1947; and correspondence, 1944, of the Michigan Municipal Finance Commission, Tax Study Advisory Committee with letters of D. Hale Brake, Harry F. Kelly, George P. McCallum, and E. Blythe Stason. The scrapbooks of clippings are useful for their documentation of league activities.
Subjects:
Benton Harbor (Mich.).; Grand Rapids (Mich.).; Holland (Mich.).; Lansing (Mich.).; Municipal government--Michigan.; Taxation--Michigan.
Contributors:
Brake, D. Hale, 1891- .; Brooks, Earnest C.; Cady, Alvah P.; Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.; McCallum, George P. (George Porterfield), 1871-1952.; Michigan Municipal Finance Commission.; Michigan Municipal Finance Commission. Tax Study Advisory Committee.; Stason, E. Blythe (Edwin Blythe), 1891-1972.; Taggart, Ganson, 1873-1959.; Troyer, Laird J.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Organizational records
  - Correspondence of League Director with
    - Earnest C. Brooks, 1928-1936 (Holland mayor) (Box 1)
    - Alvah P. Cady, 1928-1936 (Benton Harbor city attorney) (Box 1)
    - Ganson Taggart, 1928-1939 (Grand Rapids city attorney) (Box 1)
    - Laird J. Troyer, 1929-1936 (Lansing mayor) (Box 1)
    - Detroit officials (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous staff field reports, 1934-1947 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous reports, memoranda and historical material (Box 1)
  - Clippings and other papers concerning charter revisions in Michigan municipalities (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1935-1972 containing clippings and other League materials (Box 2)
  - Papers, 1944 concerning Tax Study Advisory Committee of the Michigan Municipal Finance Commission (Box 2)